Guide to the Tina Darragh literary papers collection, 1974-2017 MS2366
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Tina Darragh literary papers
1974-2016
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Darragh, Tina
MS2366
6 Linear Feet
This collection contains published poetical works collected by Tina Darragh. The collected works include works by Tina Darragh and her conteporaries.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Tina Darragh writings and Non-Tina Darragh writings.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Tina Darragh, March 30, 2017 (2017.014)
Biographical / Historical
Tina Darragh, a local poet, has writing poetry since the late 1960s. Born in Pittsburgh Pennsylvania, Darragh moved to Washington D.C. to attend Trinity University. While at Trinity, Darragh became interested in writing poetry and met many other local writers. Darragh would meet up with these writers at Mass Transit and later at Folio, local community bookshops. Some of the poets she worked with include, Diane Ward, Joan Retallack, and P. Inman. These poets came together to form the east coast branch of the Language group of poetry. This style of poetry emphasizes the reader's role in the work. Darragh currently lives in Greenbelt, MD with her husband P. Inman.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains published works by the poet Tina Darragh and other publications collected by her between 1974 and 2017.
Bib#
17257788
Poetry -- 20th century; Poetry; Poetry -- 21st century
- Tina Darragh writings, 1974-2016; Series 1; 3 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by publication.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains published works by Tina Darragh between 1974-2016.
  - Aerial #4 and #5, 1988-1989; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Art & Con, 1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bad I.O.U. (Yockadot), 2007; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Belladonna, 2010; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Belladonna Elderly #8, 2009; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Big Allis #5, 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Boog Reader #4, Undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Boundary 2, 1985-1986; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bridge Street Reading, 1997; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Buffalo Readings, 2014; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Center for Book Arts, 2003; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chain Vol. 1, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chain Vol. 4, 1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Crayon Vol. 4, 2004; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - DCAC Readings, 1995; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - DC Poetry Oral History, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Deep Eco Pre, 2010; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dog City 2, 1980; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Double Change, 2016; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Drawing Center, 2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - deep rim instructions, 1999; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ecopoetics No. 415, 2004-2005; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Enough, 2003; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Etruscan Jetty, 1996; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Exposed Faces, 1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - i.e. reader (Baltimore), 2009; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - I'll Drown My Book, 2012; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ironwood 20, 1982; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - La Bas, 1978; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - La Lengua Radical, 1992; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lipstick Eleven No. 3, 2002; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Long News Issue 3, 1992; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mass Transit, 1974-1987; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Moving Borders, 1998; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Non/Narrative (Poetics Journal Number 5), 1985; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - O Anthology, 1991; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Opposable Dumbs, 2002; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Paris Review 86, 1982; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Pessimistic Labor, 1984; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Philly Talks, 1998; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Poetry Project, 1983-2009; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Primary Writing, 1984; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Reading Flyers etc., 1984; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rett Kopi, 2007; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Reviews, 1992; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sink 2, 1986; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Talisman #8, 1992; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - War and Peace 2, 2005; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Washington Review, 1982-1985; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Xa (audiotape), 1979; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Yellow Field, 2005-2016; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Non-Tina Darragh writings, 1976-2017; Series 2
  Arranged alphabetically by poet surname.
  This series contains publications by poets, collected by Tina Darragh, between 1976-2017.
  - Al-Mutanabi (Corcoran), 2013; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Time Dlugos, 1990; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Buck Downs, 1999-2016; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Lynne Dreyer, 2015; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cathy Eisenhower, 2015; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Jeremy Gardner, 2006; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - P. Inman, 1986-2007; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - P. Inman, 1976-2013; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Beth Joselow, 1983; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Michael Lally, 1995; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Doug Lang, Undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Douglas Messerli, 1979; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Tom Orange, 2002-2009; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Joan Retallack, 1985-1994; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Phyllis Rosenzweig, 2014; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Joe Ross, 1990; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Self-Portrait (Lally, Lang, etc.), 1976; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Rod Smith, 2003-2015; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ann Stoddard, 2004; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Tangent, 2007; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Tangent, 2008; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The Tinklers, Undated; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mark Wallace, Undated; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Diane Ward, 1984-2000; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - ZimZalla 002, 2017; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - ZimZalla 003, 2017; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - ZimZalla 006, 2017; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - ZimZalla 009, 2017; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - ZimZalla 011, 2017; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - ZimZalla 014, 2017; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - ZimZalla 016, 2017; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - ZimZalla 017, 2017; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 4)